ADARSH V S

14 March 2000 8129272366 adarshvs6665@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/adarshvs6665/

A 2-year-experienced software developer specialising in back-end development with a strong proficiency in TypeScript and Node.js. I have a proven track record of successfully delivering projects ranging from serverless to microservices and monolithic architectures. I am committed to continuous learning and innovation in the everevolving tech landscape.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

LANGUAGES : C++, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, PHP

BACK-END : Express, Flask FRONT-END : ReactJS, Flutter

CLOUD : AWS

OTHER : Git, Agile, Linux, Docker, Jenkins, MYSQL

SOFT SKILLS

- Growth mindset
- Adaptability
- · Emotional intelligence
- Critical thinking

EDUCATION

2018-2022 **B.TECH**

University College of Engineering, Kariavattom

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

zDistanceLab November 2022 - Present

- Developed REST APIs from scratch, ensuring structured and maintainable code.
- Designed efficient database architecture and optimised SQL queries for improved performance.
- Utilised microservices architecture for building scalable, resilient, and maintainable systems.
- Utilised AWS services for deploying and monitoring the applications.
- Developed front end applications using React and HTML.
- Designed software architectures and specifications to meet client requirements.
- Participated in code reviews, and sharing best practices to enhance team productivity and code quality.
- Performed web scraping from various websites using Selenium, providing clients with valuable data extraction and automation solutions.

Freelancer 2021 - 2022

- Successfully completed multiple freelance projects, showcasing adaptability across diverse client needs.
- Leveraged expertise in Java and Node.js to create efficient, scalable, and maintainable server-side applications for clients.

- Expertise in creating responsive front end using UI libraries such as Material UI and Bootstrap, enhancing the user experience across different devices and screen sizes.
- Developed mobile applications using flutter and NodeJS.

KEY PROJECTS

Inlife

Predicts the ideal architectural style for clients of an interior design and architectural firm by utilizing image selection and surveys.

Used: Express, MySQL, AWS, Docker

- Designed the server and database architecture.
- Developed, tested and deployed the application.

Employee Portal

An internal application developed for zDistanceLab to streamline employee management, allowing employees to request leaves and HR to efficiently manage leave requests through approval or rejection.

Used: Express, React, MUI, MySQL, AWS, Docker

- Designed the front end framework using React and MUI.
- Developed and enhanced key project components, including authentication and authorisation, email service integration, and user management APIs.

VisualCoding

An interactive game designed for mid school students to learn coding.

Used: Javascript, Aframe, PixiJS, AWS

- Designed challenging levels for the 3D VisualCoding game using using Aframe.
- Developed the 2D version of VisualCoding from scratch and deployed it in AWS.

PDMS

Designed and implemented a blockchain-based solution for storing and managing patient data in an educational context, ensuring secure and tamper-proof records for students.

Used: Express, MySQL, AWS, Web3JS, Solidity

 Developed the end to end application for managing patient records using etherium blockchain technology and smart contracts.

Chatbot

Interactive chatbot to enhance user engagement and information access for a college website.

Used: Express, RASA, React

- Prepared data and trained an ML model using RASA framework.
- Implemented the user interface with React and backend using NodeJS.

VideoIDE

Collaborated on the development of an innovative platform inspired by the MIT Scratch IDE. Contributed to the implementation of critical project features, including the cloud upload feature and the central functionality of the application, ensuring seamless user experiences and enhanced project capabilities.